<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>git.fosscommunity.in on Vinay Keshava</title>
    <link>/tags/git.fosscommunity.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content in git.fosscommunity.in on Vinay Keshava</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 20:01:24 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/git.fosscommunity.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Software Freedom Camp 2021 Snikket</title>
      <link>/posts/software-freedom-camp-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 20:01:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/software-freedom-camp-2021/</guid>
      <description>Back to writing after a 2-month long Semester End Exam !!!!.
Everyone uses messaging platforms like WhatsApp, Facebook, Signal, Telegram, and various other applications to communicate with people, in this blog post I would like to introduce to XMPP Protocol( Extensible Messaging and Presence Protocol), XMPP is an open, decentralized universal messaging standard for instant messaging, voice/video calls. Many Applications or Clients are built using the XMPP protocol due to its open nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>git.fosscommunity.in Server Update</title>
      <link>/posts/git-fosscommunity-in-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 20:01:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/git-fosscommunity-in-update/</guid>
      <description>Ahh, my first blog post. Good Beginnings (:
Excited!!
This blog post is dedicated to sharing my experience with updating the FSCI’s GitLab instance git.fosscommunity.in update.
FSCI runs a free instance of GitLab Community Edition at git.fosscommunity.in for collaborative software development.
FSCI also hosts and maintains a lot of services for the community, you can check out the services here, these services are managed by volunteers.
After joining Software Freedom Camp 2021 Diversity Edition( Online mentorship programme organized by Free Software Community of India(FSCI) ) as a learner and I met a bunch of people who discuss about Free/Libre/Open Source Software and educate people about why it is important to use free software in our life maintaining freedom and privacy in this era of technology.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
