<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vinay Keshava – Logs</title>
    <link>/tags/logs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Logs on Vinay Keshava</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/logs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>WILY</title>
      <link>/blog/wily/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/wily/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3&gt;What I Learnt Yesterday(WILY)&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-i-learnt-yesterdaywily&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-i-learnt-yesterdaywily&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;WILY is a name I rephrased to log all my daily learnings.I started this two months ago, where I log about what I learnt yesterday.Everyday is a learning day it can be tech, some commands or some life lessons experienced throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired from  &lt;a href=&#34;https://writingcooperative.com/zettelkasten-how-one-german-scholar-was-so-freakishly-productive-997e4e0ca125&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Zettelkasten&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point of time in our lives we would want to relearn a few things after a few days/weeks but the effort to find resources for a specific topic can be time consuming.
I learnt a lot of stuff during engineering but I don&amp;rsquo;t remember any thing now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was using Notion as my documentation app, used to make notes within a notion workspace,it has an option to export to PDF and also share an article with a public link.
Then I found this beautiful hextra hugo theme, where i can design to my custom look and needs. Took a few weeks to setup this theme locally,with the help of the hextra  theme maintainer on GitHub.
Now everytime I learn something new i write and save it in a markdown file, so thats its easy to add back to the docs.
I also love the &lt;code&gt;docs&lt;/code&gt; feature of this theme,making it beautiful and easy to search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish to log all my daily learnings with more sincere effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you until next time.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
