<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts of Vinay Keshava</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Vinay Keshava</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 20:01:24 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Debian Maintainer Now !!!!</title>
      <link>/posts/debian-maintainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 20:01:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/debian-maintainer/</guid>
      <description>a debian maintainer now !!!</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am excited to share with you all that I have recently become a <a href="https://nm.debian.org/process/1173/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Debian maintainer</a>!!
Thanks to amazing debian community.</p>
<p>It all started with <a href="https://camp.fsci.in" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Software Freedom Camp</a>, <a href="https://ravish0007.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ravish</a> my college super senior (we were a part of college linux club) introduced me to software freedom camp organized by FSCI, since then i was a noob hopping between various distro&rsquo;s from kali linux to other debian based distros to arch !
I had previously written my experience of attending software freedom camp <a href="https://vinay-keshava.gitlab.io/posts/softwarefreedomcamp2021snikket/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p>I started with packaging node modules initially without any knowledge of javascript/nodejs, before packaging new module i tried to upgrade few node packages to new upstream,it was difficult at first understanding the packaging process. <a href="https://tracker.debian.org/pkg/node-prosemirror-view" target="_blank" rel="noopener">node-prosemirror-view</a> was the first node module i packaged, cut to 20'23, i maintain few ruby and golang packages most of them which are gitlab dependencies, here is the <a href="https://qa.debian.org/developer.php?login=vinaykeshava@disroot.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">list</a> of packages i maintain.Special  thanks to <a href="https://social.masto.host/@praveen" target="_blank" rel="noopener">praveen</a> for his mentoring, who is my package sponsorer.</p>
<p>Over the past six months, I have been  packaging Ruby gems and GitLab dependencies. For this gitlab update, I took on the challenge of building GitLab 15.8.4 and its major components, including <a href="https://salsa.debian.org/go-team/packages/gitaly/-/tree/upstream/15.8.4&#43;dfsg1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gitlay</a> and <a href="https://salsa.debian.org/go-team/packages/gitlab-shell/-/tree/upstream/14.15.0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitLab-shell</a>.</p>
<p>Thanks to Praveen and Bilal for their help and support during gitlab package upgrade to 15.8.4.</p>
<p>The first package as DM uploaded was <a href="https://salsa.debian.org/ruby-team/ruby-et-orbi/-/tree/debian/1.2.7-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ruby-et-orbi</a>.</p>
<p>We are also preparing GitLab for bookworm, the next release of Debian.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing to Debian</title>
      <link>/posts/contributing-to-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 20:01:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/contributing-to-debian/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to Debian through packaging </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Debian</h1><p>Debian is a GNU/Linux distribution completely inclinded towards Free Software philosophy, maintained by the community.</p>
<p>Before talking about how i started contributing to debian, i would like to talk about the camp organized by FSCI
It is an online free mentorship programme organized by <a href="https://fsci.in" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Free Software Community of India</a> ,introducing people
to Free Software.<a href="https://ravish0007.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ravish</a> introduced me to 2021 <a href="https://camp.fsci.in" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FSCI&rsquo;s camp</a>, and there i
got introduced to Debian Packaging through <a href="https://wiki.debian.org/DebianDeveloper" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Debian Developers</a> and <a href="https://wiki.debian.org/DebianMaintainer" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Debian Maintainers</a>.</p>
<p>During the project phase of the camp, i choosed to work on Debian Packaging and System Administration(here is my
<a href="https://git.fosscommunity.in/community/camp/-/wikis/Proposals/Debian-Packaging-and-System-Administration/Vinay-Keshava" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Project Proposal</a>)</p>
<h1>Debian Packages and my Story !!</h1><p>Debian has roughly over 51,000 packages, these packages are installable through apt, just like &ldquo;sudo apt install nano&rdquo;.
I always wanted to know how &ldquo;sudo apt install nano&rdquo; works !.</p>
<p>During the project phase of the camp <a href="https://social.masto.host/@praveen" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Praveen</a> my mentor of the project,a <a href="https://wiki.debian.org/DebianDeveloper" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Debian Developer</a> himself
suggested to get started by packaging node packages(dependencies of <a href="https://tracker.debian.org/pkg/gitlab" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gitlab</a>).
A big Thanks to praveen for teaching packaging from scratch, also answering my useless questions and also sponsoring my packages to debian.
Initially i found it very difficult to understand it,but the community was so welcoming, they were helping and assisting me by clearing all my doubts through matrix.</p>
<p>I took a lot of time to learn,tried to spend more time in learning  during hectic schedule of college and also i gave up hope many times and restarted it.
So initial task was to setup the <a href="https://wiki.debian.org/DebianUnstable" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Debian Unstable environment </a> and rebuilding the existing simple node-pretty-ms package, and then tried a simple
package update and then went to continue packaging few node modules.</p>
<p>I currently <a href="https://qa.debian.org/developer.php?login=vinaykeshava@disroot.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">maintain</a> around two node modules as of today, looking forward to maintain more packages in debian.
All the communication happens mainly through mailing list or irc of respective <a href="https://wiki.debian.org/Teams" target="_blank" rel="noopener">teams</a>.</p>
<h1>Further Development</h1><p>Looking forward to contribute and hangout with the awesome debian community and learn more.</p>
<div class="code-block relative mt-6 first:mt-0 group/code"><pre><code id="code-block-0">    :wq</code></pre><div class="opacity-0 transition group-hover/code:opacity-100 flex gap-1 absolute m-[11px] right-0 top-0">
    <button class="code-copy-btn group/copybtn transition-all active:opacity-50 bg-primary-700/5 border border-black/5 text-gray-600 hover:text-gray-900 rounded-md p-1.5 dark:bg-primary-300/10 dark:border-white/10 dark:text-gray-400 dark:hover:text-gray-50" title="Copy code" data-clipboard-target="#code-block-0">
      <svg class="group-[.copied]/copybtn:hidden pointer-events-none h-4 w-4" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" fill="none" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2"><path stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" d="M8 16H6a2 2 0 01-2-2V6a2 2 0 012-2h8a2 2 0 012 2v2m-6 12h8a2 2 0 002-2v-8a2 2 0 00-2-2h-8a2 2 0 00-2 2v8a2 2 0 002 2z" /></svg>
      <svg class="hidden group-[.copied]/copybtn:block success-icon pointer-events-none h-4 w-4" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" fill="none" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-width="2" stroke="currentColor" aria-hidden="true"><path stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" d="M5 13l4 4L19 7"/></svg>
    </button>
  </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Freedom Camp 2021 Snikket</title>
      <link>/posts/software-freedom-camp-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 20:01:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/software-freedom-camp-2021/</guid>
      <description>Learnings from software freedom camp</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Back to writing after a 2-month long Semester End Exam !!!!.<br>
Everyone uses messaging platforms like WhatsApp, Facebook, Signal, Telegram, and various other applications to communicate with people, in this blog post I would like to introduce to XMPP Protocol( Extensible Messaging and Presence Protocol), <strong>XMPP</strong> is an open, decentralized universal messaging standard for instant messaging, voice/video calls.   Many Applications or Clients are built using the XMPP protocol due to its open nature. Platforms like WhatsApp, Telegram, Signal impose vendor lock-in wherein the user using the product or service cannot transit to the competitor’s product/service. To overcome vendor lock-in issues and privacy issues one of the minimal, simple best solutions is to set up a Snikket server of your own, where you can own your data.</p>
<h1>What is Snikket</h1><p><a href="https://snikket.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Snikket</a> is a simple, customized messaging platform that is different from other messaging apps like Whatsapp, Telegram. Snikket is a decentralized messaging platform which means anyone can host their snikket server on their cloud, it allows everyone to host their server.   <br>
Snikket is free software, a privacy-friendly messaging platform based on XMPP protocol, it can be self-hosted by anyone. Snikket provides an android application client to connect to any XMPP servers and using a snikket account you choose any XMPP clients if you want to connect using android applications like monocles chat, blabber, Snikket app other desktop clients recommended are dino-im and gajim.</p>
<h1>Experience of Running Snikket Server</h1><p>Snikket is my first self-hosted service, before talking about the experience of running the snikket server I would like to talk about <a href="https://camp.fsci.in/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Software Freedom camp 2021 </a>,the camp is organized by the Free Software Community of India. As a part of the camp initially, learners were made to understand the philosophy and intention behind free software. Later during the project phase, learners were allowed to choose certain available topics proposed by the mentor. <br>
After joining the sfcamp as a learner, I choose to learn system administration and Debian packaging, under system administration one of the deliverables was to set up a Snikket server of my own.<br>
To run any snikket server basic requirements are a domain name and a VPS (Virtual Private Server )to run your snikket server. I had signed up for the Github Student Developer pack through the pack got the free domain from name.com and I choose Amazon Web Services Free Tier as my VPS.</p>
<div class="code-block relative mt-6 first:mt-0 group/code"><pre><code id="code-block-0">  Snikket is all about the
        DNS
        Docker
        Daemons</code></pre><div class="opacity-0 transition group-hover/code:opacity-100 flex gap-1 absolute m-[11px] right-0 top-0">
    <button class="code-copy-btn group/copybtn transition-all active:opacity-50 bg-primary-700/5 border border-black/5 text-gray-600 hover:text-gray-900 rounded-md p-1.5 dark:bg-primary-300/10 dark:border-white/10 dark:text-gray-400 dark:hover:text-gray-50" title="Copy code" data-clipboard-target="#code-block-0">
      <svg class="group-[.copied]/copybtn:hidden pointer-events-none h-4 w-4" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" fill="none" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2"><path stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" d="M8 16H6a2 2 0 01-2-2V6a2 2 0 012-2h8a2 2 0 012 2v2m-6 12h8a2 2 0 002-2v-8a2 2 0 00-2-2h-8a2 2 0 00-2 2v8a2 2 0 002 2z" /></svg>
      <svg class="hidden group-[.copied]/copybtn:block success-icon pointer-events-none h-4 w-4" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" fill="none" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-width="2" stroke="currentColor" aria-hidden="true"><path stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" d="M5 13l4 4L19 7"/></svg>
    </button>
  </div>
</div>
<p>Snikket also has an option of creating circles, limiting users to that circle only, although any user can talk to any individual by providing an XMPP or Snikket username. Snikket uses an invite-based procedure for account creation on the server. Only the admin can have the authority to create an invite link. Snikket also supports audio and video calls of great speed, these are some of the <a href="https://snikket.org/app/features/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">features</a> of the snikket application. I have been using Snikket and invited most of my friends to my Snikket server. Initially, it took time to make them understand how it is completely different from other messaging platforms. Later educated them about how decentralization, vendor lock-in works and then introduced them to Snikket and other XMPP-based clients.<br>
The learning while setting up the snikket server was got introduced to Docker Container, Domain Name System( DNS ), how server logs are checked, and debugging the errors.</p>
<h1>Guide to Setup Snikket Server</h1><p>Here is the quickstart guide to setup the <a href="https://snikket.org/service/quickstart/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">snikket server </a>, this is the official guide by Snikket to setup the snikket server .
The detailed documentation is <a href="https://github.com/snikket-im/snikket-server/tree/master/docs" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.
Snikket requires few ports to be open for communication refer <a href="https://github.com/snikket-im/snikket-server/blob/master/docs/advanced/firewall.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this </a> which clearly mentions the firewall rules and ports required.
Snikket Source code <a href="https://github.com/snikket-im" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p>Thanks to <a href="https://ravish0007.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ravish</a> and <a href="https://blog.sahilister.in" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sahil</a> for helping to set up the Snikket server.</p>
<h1>Next Goals</h1> - Reverse Proxy by Nginx .
<p>Bye for now .</p>
<div class="code-block relative mt-6 first:mt-0 group/code"><pre><code id="code-block-1">    :wq</code></pre><div class="opacity-0 transition group-hover/code:opacity-100 flex gap-1 absolute m-[11px] right-0 top-0">
    <button class="code-copy-btn group/copybtn transition-all active:opacity-50 bg-primary-700/5 border border-black/5 text-gray-600 hover:text-gray-900 rounded-md p-1.5 dark:bg-primary-300/10 dark:border-white/10 dark:text-gray-400 dark:hover:text-gray-50" title="Copy code" data-clipboard-target="#code-block-1">
      <svg class="group-[.copied]/copybtn:hidden pointer-events-none h-4 w-4" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" fill="none" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2"><path stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" d="M8 16H6a2 2 0 01-2-2V6a2 2 0 012-2h8a2 2 0 012 2v2m-6 12h8a2 2 0 002-2v-8a2 2 0 00-2-2h-8a2 2 0 00-2 2v8a2 2 0 002 2z" /></svg>
      <svg class="hidden group-[.copied]/copybtn:block success-icon pointer-events-none h-4 w-4" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" fill="none" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-width="2" stroke="currentColor" aria-hidden="true"><path stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" d="M5 13l4 4L19 7"/></svg>
    </button>
  </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>git.fosscommunity.in Server Update</title>
      <link>/posts/git-fosscommunity-in-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 20:01:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/git-fosscommunity-in-update/</guid>
      <description>Updating git.fosscommunity.in</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ahh, my first blog post.   Good Beginnings  (:<br>
Excited!!</p>
<p>This blog post is dedicated to sharing my experience with updating the FSCI’s GitLab instance <a href="https://git.fosscommunity.in/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">git.fosscommunity.in</a> update.<br>
<a href="https://fsci.in/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FSCI</a> runs a free instance of GitLab Community Edition at <a href="https://git.fosscommunity.in" target="_blank" rel="noopener">git.fosscommunity.in</a> for collaborative software development.<br>
FSCI also hosts and maintains a lot of services for the community, you can check out the services <a href="https://fsci.in/#poddery" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>, these services are managed by volunteers.</p>
<p>After joining  <a href="https://camp.fsci.in" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Software Freedom Camp 2021 Diversity Edition</strong></a>( Online mentorship programme organized by Free Software Community of India(FSCI) ) as a learner and I met a bunch of people who discuss about <a href="https://ravidwivedi.in/posts/free-software-explained-simply/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Free/Libre/Open Source Software</a> and educate people about why it is important to use free software in our life maintaining freedom and privacy in this era of technology.
<br></p>
<p>Along with <a href="https://ravish0007.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ravish</a> and <a href="https://blog.sahilister.in" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sahilister</a>  we all updated it from GitLab v14.4.2 to Gitlab v14.4.4 it was a Security update, it took a lot of my time to update and upgrade the instance.</p>
<p>All thanks to  <a href="https://ravish0007.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ravish</a> and <a href="https://blog.sahilister.in" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sahilister</a> for helping and teaching me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>